Inu!
Hey, lady.
Hope I'm not too late.
Please! Silica!
You're here!
I can't believe it!
We couldn't send this one out.
We came as soon as we could.
Have you seen yourself lately?
You're all torn up.
You push yourself way too hard!
We brought everyone with us.
We can take it from here!
Everyone?
Those big stun ones are the bad guys!
Vanguard, with me!
Drive them back!
Rearguard?
Fall back with the Underworld!
Check your spells!
Just so we're clear, this
ain't nothing personal.
All the same, you're gonna pay
for what you did to our friend.
You'll pay big time.
Alright, now that that's settled,
here comes the pain, you bastards!
I'm not going to be able to run away.
Look, I'm not going to
be able to run away.
I don't know if I'm not sure.
I don't know about what you can do.
But I don't have to worry about something.
I don't have to worry about it.
It's simply very important to difference.
You knew you might not get them back,
but still, you converted your characters.
I just, I'm sorry.
What are you talking about, Asuna?
Why do you think we work
so hard in SAO and ALO4?
It's this, to protect the people
we love whenever and wherever.
You're right, as usual.
Thanks, guys.
Wait, the Underworld's
on a closed network.
Who told you how to log on to it?
I'm surprised you'd ask.
It should be obvious.
Yeah, it was Yui.
She told us everything that was going
on with the Underworld and its people.
We've never seen her
get so emotional before.
Thanks for looking out for us, Yui.
Um, Lady Asuna?
Who exactly are these new people?
Are they knights or mercenaries?
Oh, they're with me.
They're my best friends.
They came from the real world to help us.
Thank you for your assistance.
I am so relieved.
To tell you the truth,
I thought everyone from your
world, aside from Lady Asuna,
of course, were brutes
like those soldiers.
Well, of course we're not all like that.
I'm Lisbeth.
Put her there, Mr.
Knight.
I'm Silica.
It's nice to meet you.
Oh, right. Apologies.
I am Renly.
A pleasure to meet you both.
Hey, Liz.
How many people converted in with you?
Um, oh yeah.
Only a little over 2,000 came along.
I tried to get more, but even after
spilling my guts to the council,
that's all I could get.
It's more than enough.
But if reconverting is an
option for real worlders,
this could turn into a war of attrition.
We should focus on healing and
keep the front line from spreading.
We need a support unit.
Liz, Silica, could you fall
back with 200 and form one?
We'll get right on it.
Don't worry, we'll be ready.
I know how skilled you are in battle,
but if you're okay with it,
I need you to teach healing.
My world doesn't have sacred art.
So I thought if you and your
priests taught our warriors,
it might give us the edge we need.
Oh, yes.
I'd be happy to.
All right, then.
I'm heading to the front line.
Now that everyone's here, we won't lose.
We can beat them, I know it!
Together, we will win!
Man, I hope I logged them all in, in time.
You did.
I'm sure of it.
Damn it.
I should have anticipated
something like this.
When those girls told us the hijackers
logged American players into the underworld,
I just went numb.
And on top of that, for some AI in
Asuna's phone to be the one that spots it,
I should turn in my keyboard.
Well, it happened the way it happened.
Now that all these
civilians are logged in,
Project Alicization
isn't a secret anymore.
It's out in the public.
Yeah, that's a huge problem.
But compared to the
enemy getting their hands
on Alice and using her
to pilot war drones?
I prefer it.
She's special.
She's not an AI anymore.
Alice is a new type of humanity, born
and raised in an alternate world.
She's the future.
And you knew that way before we did.
Isn't that right, Kirito?
Huh?
What the...
Hey, Harenko!
It's his Fluctlight!
Check out the activity log!
What caused those spikes?
Don't know.
Whatever they were, they triggered
his consciousness at those two points.
But the log says he's still out of it.
Something made an impression though.
The timestamps check them.
I'll bet you anything those are
when the girls in the STLs dove in.
They are the same time.
Is it possible that all it took to make
him react were friends of his? Showing up.
Nah.
The kind of damage
Kirito's got can't be fixed
by some kind of poetic
explanation like that.
There's got to be a more logical reason.
The self.
The subject.
The image he has of
himself that defines him.
Could there be a backup
of that quantum pattern?
somewhere?
No, of course there isn't.
We never made a copy
of Kirito's Fluctlight.
Hey.
And even if there was a copy,
it'd be impossible to extract his
self-image and transfer it over.
Higa, wait a sec. Maybe.
If there Was an active quantum pattern
that could Connect to his Fluctlight?
but where would we find that?
Would you listen?
I'm listening.
The subject observes.
The object is observed.
But you can't separate them
that clearly and easily.
Huh?
Subjective and objective
are just philosophical
concepts that explain the
relationship of things.
And since humans are social
creatures, not isolated individuals,
you have an image of others in your
mind, and they have one of you in theirs.
It's like we're all connected, up to a
point, in a kind of network, if you will.
Wouldn't you agree?
The image of me in others?
it's like a backup of the self-image
that's it we got it we can restore
his subjective self-image we have the
data it's in the floodlights of the
people he's closest to all right we
want to extract that data we need an STL
and reproducing it'll take more than
one person we're gonna need two no three
people.
Hey Keeks, the girls diving from
Roppongi, how tight are they with Kirito?
Are they close?
Yeah, they both are.
You heard about the Death
Gun case six months ago.
Sinon helped Kirito crack that one.
And Leafa is Kirito's little sister.
This'll work!
We got what we need to save Kirito!
We can restore his self-image!
We'll extract the image
of him stored in their
Fluctlights and connect
it to the damaged regions!
That should Repair his subjective
self hot down this is gonna work.
Oh no what am i saying this won't work?
The equipment i need to run everything
is in the main freaking control room.
Don't beat yourself up
Higa we have a better
shot at restoring Kirito
now and that's good.
But for now we wait once
our guests leave and
the ocean turtles ours
again we'll get to work.
That'll be too late.
We have to do it now.
If the Asahi sends commandos to board us,
and they end up fighting the
hijackers in the main shaft,
it could knock out the power in Subcon.
If that happens,
Kirito's STL would shut down and
he'd be logged out of the Underworld.
Unconscious.
us.
In that state, we'd never get him to pass
the initialization stage, and he'll never
be able to connect to the STL again.
We can't wait.
We have to try.
Now, right now, while
he and those girls are
still in the underworld.
It's our only shot at saving him.
I'll do
it, Keeks. I'll go.
I don't follow.
Where are you going?
Alright, here's my plan.
There's a cable duct running down
the stern side of the main shaft.
It connects STL-2,
Kirito's room, to main con.
I'm going to climb down the duct until
I get to the maintenance connector.
I'll patch into it, and I should be
able to control Kirito's STL from there.
But that connector is on the same
side of the bulkhead as the hijackers.
If they find out you're in the duct,
they'll breach it and attack you from below.
Right, so I'll need a decoy.
Yes, you do. But who?
Not who.
I wouldn't want anyone here
to risk their life too.
We'll unlock the bulkhead door,
then send some thing that can't get
killed on a walk downstairs to Minigun.
Him.
Oh, I get it. Ichemon.
Your robot?
But all it can do is walk.
It can't fight or run or anything else.
Once they see him coming,
they're just gonna blow it to
pieces and that's the end of that.
It sucks for Ichiemon, but
he's the best decoy we have.
Besides, with how he looks, they might
think he'll explode if they shoot him.
Well, he'll definitely get their
attention, that's for sure.
At the very least,
they might think we sent
him down there because
we're planning something
even more ridiculous.
They can't ignore him.
That's the point of sending him.
Then, while the hijackers
are dealing with Ichiemon,
I'll climb into the
lower part of the duct,
patch into that connector, and
operate Kirito's STL from there.
We have two robots.
Hmm.
We should send the aim on. Nope.
Like I told Asuna before this
nightmare started, he's not ready yet.
He needs a Fluctlight to
pilot and keep him in balance,
or he'll just roll down the stairs.
Damn.
Higa, I'm not so sure about this.
Even if the decoy works,
when you're in that duct you're vulnerable,
and if they find you in there...
You should take an agent to
keep an eye out while you work.
No way.
The JSDF agents have to stay
here to keep all of you safe.
Besides, the duct is way too
narrow for most folks to fit.
But not for a skinny little nerd like me.
Don't you worry.
I'll be down and back before you know it.
Hirito risked everything for this project.
If it weren't for him, Alice's Fluck Light
wouldn't have developed into what it is.
He tried to protect her.
That's why he's in this mess.
And that's why if there's a chance
to save him I have to take it doesn't
matter if I'm risking my life it's
the only way I can make it up to him
um if you don't mind I'd like to go
with you and be your bodyguard I'm
pretty skinny myself but there's enough
meat on my bones to stop a bullet
But if it comes to that, I'm also the
one in charge of cable maintenance here,
so it could be useful.
Uh, to be honest, I'm not 100 %
sure how far down that connector is.
If you're okay with it,
I could use the help.
Thanks, Yuna.
How boring.
Your soul is too thick
and heavy, too simple.
It sticks to my tongue.
All you can think about is killing me.
And now you are done.
That's what you'd think.
I still got some life in me.
Just a little longer.
Where is it?
Where'd it go?
Over there.
No, it wasn't that way.
Thirty seconds left.
There.
Found it.
579, 580, 581, 582.
Now what could you possibly be up to?
I miss dammit forgive me Asuna and Alice.
He got me
Hey, I thought I told you to go back.
This is the first time you
disobeyed me, stubborn old dragon.
Oh Shagami, thanks for giving me
one more chance, I won't waste it.
With the time-splitting
sword, I can cut two ways.
The future and the past, you bastard.
Ahhhh!
It's so warm.
Father…
Uncle?
I remember.
I was captured by Emperor Vecta.
Commander!
Uncle!
Uncle, no.
Come on, kiddo. Don't cry.
We all gotta go sometime, and
this was just mine, that's all.
You have to handle things on
your own now, but she'll be fine.
I know it.
You are my apprentice after
all, and my precious daughter.
Oh well, at least we
went out in style, huh?
Indeed.
So many people will mourn your passing.
Consider yourself blessed.
My lady, fancy seeing your ghost?
Here, I'm not a ghost, silly.
This is just the me that
exists in your memory,
the memory you had of Administrator
One, which you held dear in your soul.
Really,
if you say so, my lady?
Wow!
If that's how it is, then it's
good to know that you—I remember.
remember I never could smile like that.
I find it odd you don't despise me.
After all, I was the one who
forced immortality on you.
And I kept robbing you of your memories.
I'll admit, after the first
hundred years it got old.
But even so, my life
was pretty interesting.
That's for sure.
Good then.
I'm sorry, Fanatio.
But it looks like we won't be
seeing each other for a while.
Good luck down there.
Make sure to give our baby
a happy life. You hear?
They're going!
Do not worry, my commander.
I swear, I will raise our child well.
They will be strong and brave
and proud like their father.
Well, look who's up.
Good morning, boss.
I guess you got your ass
kicked in there, huh?
What's the latest?
I did everything like you wanted.
I sent in 50,000 players from the U
.S., and they're tearing it up in there.
Oh, and that jackass
Vassago got killed, too.
But he got excited about something.
Had me convert his Gamer
account and dove back in.
Really? Interesting.
Not a bad idea.
Critter, convert that
account to the Underworld.
I still need to take care of some things.
The next episode of SENDOW